(
"ai_sub_version": "1.9.1",
"subtitles_prompt_version": 2,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": "gemini-cli:gemini-3-pro-preview",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true
),
"gemini_cli": (
"timeout": 600
)
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": true,
"fps": 1,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"encoder": "libx264"
)
),
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 1,
"subtitles": 2
),
"retry": (
"run": 3,
"max": 9,
"delay": 30
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": false,
"scrub": true
)
目指せよ快眠 勝ち取れ安眠
Aim for good sleep! Win peaceful sleep!
いざ夢の世界へ
Now, to the world of dreams!
理想の眠りを求めて
Seeking the ideal slumber.
さあ 始めよう おやすみ
Come, let's begin. Goodnight.
ノンレム睡眠 レム睡眠 ノンレム睡眠 レム睡眠
Non-REM sleep, REM sleep, Non-REM sleep, REM sleep.
私は囚われの姫
I am a captive princess.
魔王の城の中で
Inside the Demon King's castle.
一人閉じ込められては
Being locked up all alone,
毎日ひたすらに眠ってます
I just sleep earnestly every day.
今宵も布団に入り
Tonight, too, getting into the futon.
スヤスヤリスト生活
The 'Suyarist' life.
枕もシーツも
Both the pillow and the sheets...
硬くて眠れない
...are too hard, I can't sleep.
（君も寝具にしてやろうか）
(Shall I turn you into bedding too?)
目指せよ快眠 勝ち取れ安眠
Aim for good sleep! Win peaceful sleep!
いざ夢の世界へ
Now, to the world of dreams!
ふかふかの枕手に入れて
Getting a fluffy pillow,
この疲れ癒したい
I want to heal this fatigue.
恐れず前進 ほぐせよ全身
Advance without fear! Relax your whole body!
瞼を閉じたなら
If you close your eyelids...
すべすべのシーツの上で
...on the smooth sheets.
さあ 始めよう おやすみ
Come, let's begin. Goodnight.
ノンレム睡眠 レム睡眠 ノンレム睡眠 レム睡眠
Non-REM sleep, REM sleep, Non-REM sleep, REM sleep.
私は囚われの姫
I am a captive princess.
悲鳴が響く夜に
In the night where screams echo.
一人で檻を抜け出し
Escaping the cage alone,
今日もお散歩へと行ってきます
I'm going for a walk today too.
幾多の試練も越えて
Overcoming many trials,
新たな寝具の...
Towards new bedding...
とことんまで
Until the very end,
猛毒で
with deadly poison,
死んでも眠りたい
I want to sleep even if I die!
城ごと寝具にしてやろうか
Shall I turn the whole castle into bedding?
掴めよ快眠
Seize the good sleep,
疲れて安眠
tired, so peaceful sleep,
いざ夢の向こうへ
now, to the other side of the dream!
ハイテク目覚まし
A high-tech alarm clock,
手に入れて
get it in hand,
気持ちよく目覚めたい
I want to wake up feeling good!
まだまだ前進
Still moving forward,
華麗に変身
transforming beautifully.
ごはんを食べたなら
If I've eaten my meal,
魔法のベッドにダイブして
dive into the magic bed,
さあ 始めよう
Come on, let's begin,
おやすみ
goodnight!
明日はもっと
Tomorrow will be more,
今日よりずっと
much better than today,
いい夢みれるかな
I wonder if I can have a good dream.
フワフワの羽根に包まれて
Wrapped in fluffy feathers,
心ゆくまで眠りたい
I want to sleep to my heart's content.
目指せよ快眠
Aim for good sleep,
勝ち取れ安眠
win the peaceful sleep,
いざ夢の世界へ
now, to the world of dreams!
理想の眠りを求めて
Seeking the ideal sleep,
さあ 始めよう
come on, let's begin,
おやすみ
goodnight!
もう あと5分
Just 5 more minutes...
おやすみ
goodnight!
ノンレム睡眠 レム睡眠
Non-REM sleep, REM sleep.
スヤァ
Zzz...
うぁ〜 はい こんまっする〜！
Yawn... Okay! Kon-Muscle!
ホロライブ3期生の白銀ノエルでーす！
I'm Hololive 3rd Gen, Shirogane Noel!
本日はライブに来てくれてありがとー！
Thank you for coming to the live today!
そしてハッシュタグはこちら！
And the hashtag is here!
白銀ノエル生誕祭2025 たくさんスクショして
#ShiroganeNoelBirthdayFestival2025, take lots of screenshots,
SNSに投稿してくださーい！
and please post them on social media!
今日の えー ライブのテーマなんですが
About the theme of today's live...
ま 見ての通りね 睡眠 安眠 癒しライブとなっております
Well, as you can see, it's a sleep, peaceful sleep, and healing live.
ライブ後半にかけて盛り上がっていくので
It will get more exciting towards the second half,
是非 皆様も盛り上がってください！
so everyone, please get excited too!
てな感じで
Something like that.
1曲目は「快眠！安眠！スヤリスト生活」を歌わせていただきました
For the first song, I sang 'Kaimin! Anmin! Syalist Seikatsu'.
あの曲中ね あの団長踊りながら まぁ変身したシーンがありましたけど
During the song, there was a scene where Danchou transformed while dancing...
わかった？
Did you get it?
わかったっていうか みんな気づいてる？
Or rather, did everyone notice?
ていうか おメイクがちょっと変わりました！
I mean, my makeup has changed a little!
お気づきでしょうか？
Did you notice?
まぁ具体的にね どういうところが変わったかと言いますと
Well, if I were to say specifically what parts changed...
髪の毛がですね あの サラサラによりなりました
My hair, um, became even more silky.
特に後ろとかね わかるかな？
Especially the back, can you tell?
ほら サラサラ！
Look, silky!
もうほんとに いつでも
Really, anytime,
あの シャンプーのCM 待ってます
um, I'm waiting for a shampoo commercial.
てな感じで サラサラになったのと あとおメイクもね あのちょっと変わっております
So, it became silky like that, and my makeup also changed a bit.
色んな表情ができるようになったんですけど
I've become able to make various expressions...
えーと なんか
Um, like...
なんかダイさん ノエちゃんが怒るようなこと言ってみて
Like, Dai-san! Say something that would make Noe-chan angry.
うんうん
Uh huh.
え 何？ おい
Eh, what? Hey.
ちょっと太った？
'Did you gain a little weight?'
ん〜 なに！？
Hmph... What!?
太ってないよ！ 最近ダイエット頑張ってるもん！
I haven't gained weight! I've been working hard on my diet lately!
てな感じで
Like that.
前はちょっと結構ガチ怒りって感じだったんですけど
Before, it felt like a pretty serious anger,
マイルド怒りになりました
but it has become a 'mild anger'.
はい
Yes.
ていう感じで あのちょっとね 色んな表情ができるようになったので
So like that, um, since I can make various expressions now,
それも踏まえて あのライブ見てくれると嬉しいです
I'd be happy if you watch the live with that in mind.
そして まぁノエちゃんも変わったんですけど
And, well, Noe-chan has changed too, but...
この変わったね あの お姿で さらに！
With this changed, um, appearance, furthermore!
本日のステージはこちらです！
Today's stage is this!
えー すごいね 全景… わあ！
Eh, amazing, the full view... Wow!
なんか本当 癒しって感じだよね
It really feels like 'healing', doesn't it?
もう本当に綺麗に はい 作っていただきました
It was really beautifully, yes, created for me.
まあ このね 周り？ そう 周りね
Well, this, surrounding area? Yes, the surroundings,
これ雲
these are clouds.
雲の海みたいな感じで プカプカっとなっております
It's like a sea of clouds, floating fluffy-like.
ええ
Yeah.
そしてね まぁこうやってね 雲の海から
And, well, like this, from the sea of clouds,
上もね すごーい！ 綺麗ー！
the top too, amazing! Beautiful!
なんか飾りが グルグルグルグルと回っておりますので
Like, the decorations are spinning round and round.
いやなんかね あの まぁこれからちょっとゲストパートとかもあるんですけど
Well, um, there will be guest parts from now on too, but...
なんかそれに合わせて色々変わってくみたいなので
It seems things will change in various ways to match that,
是非楽しみにしてみてください
so please look forward to it.
それでは次の曲 Let's go!
Well then, to the next song, Let's go!
僕は今
I am now...
夢旅の中
...in the middle of a dream journey.
僕は今　夢旅の中
I am currently in the middle of a dream journey,
あの星の島までも　飛んでゆける
able to fly even to that island of stars.
手のりうたうたう　僕のユメクイ
My hand-sized singing Dream Eater,
君のそばにも　たどり着ける
can find its way to your side as well.
最初に描いた　夢を思い出せなくなって
Becoming unable to recall the dream I first sketched,
頭の輪　大人になったから
because the halo over my head has grown up.
右か左かで　いつまでも迷って
Lost forever between right and left,
太陽が反転するまで　喋り込んだ
we talked until the sun turned around.
ひとつだけ　ポケットに入れてきたもの
Just one thing I brought in my pocket,
大きな　この愛を持って
holding onto this big love.
僕は今　夢旅の中
I am currently in the middle of a dream journey,
あの星の島までも　飛んでゆける
able to fly even to that island of stars.
手のりうたうたう　僕のユメクイ
My hand-sized singing Dream Eater,
君のそばにも　たどり着ける
can find its way to your side as well.
カラフルなモヤに　心を奪われ
With my heart stolen by a colorful haze,
ちょっとしたことに　躓いた
I stumbled over something trivial.
擦りむいたとこに　君がくれたのは
What you gave me for where I scraped myself,
恥ずかしいくらいの　可愛らしい絆創膏
was an embarrassingly cute bandage.
叶える度に　食いつくすユメクイ
The Dream Eater that devours every time a wish is granted.
叶える度に　また夢を見る
Every time it's granted, I dream again,
いくつになっても
no matter how old I get.
僕は今　夢旅の中
I am currently in the middle of a dream journey,
寄り道して　プレゼントを見つける
taking a detour to find a present.
手のりうたうたう　僕のユメクイ
My hand-sized singing Dream Eater,
描いた未来に　君がいつもいる
You are always there in the future I sketched.
僕は今　夢旅の中
I am currently in the middle of a dream journey,
あの星の島までも　飛んでゆける
able to fly even to that island of stars.
手のりうたうたう　僕のユメクイ
My hand-sized singing Dream Eater,
君のそばにも　たどり着ける
can find its way to your side as well.
君のそばで　ずっと夢を見る
By your side, I will dream forever.
半端ないパッパラッパッパラッパラ
It's insane, pa-pa-ra pa-pa-ra pa-pa-ra!
Hey!
限界突破ラッパッパラッパッパラ
Breaking limits, pa-pa-ra pa-pa-ra!
Hey!
毎日半端ないパッパラッパッパラッパラ
Every day is insane, pa-pa-ra pa-pa-ra pa-pa-ra!
Hey!
限界突破ラッパッパラッパッパラ
Breaking limits, pa-pa-ra pa-pa-ra!
Hey!
快適温度
Comfortable temperature.
塞ぎ込むゴースト
A depressed ghost.
余裕のない
No composure,
嫌な外的要素
Unpleasant external factors.
何の気ないと
Without a care,
超明らかに
Super obviously.
悪気もなく邪魔するどっかの
To someone somewhere getting in my way...
誰かさんに Bye Bye
...without malice, Bye Bye!
自分時間堕落タイム確保
Securing my own time, my slacking time.
5時9時を死守しますと
I will defend my 5-to-9.
さらに愛や恋や舞いも忘れずに
Without forgetting love, romance, or dancing.
とどのつまり
In the end...
オーバーワークは立ち入り禁止ですよ
Overwork is strictly prohibited!
って注意喚起もしてますよ
I'm even issuing warnings about it!
ねえ楽して上手くして
Hey, taking it easy, doing it skillfully...
生きてくって難しいな
...living like that is tough, huh.
だって安定 裏技 一夜漬け
Because stability, cheat codes, overnight cramming...
甘い蜜には罠がある
...sweet nectar always has a trap.
イヤ！
No!
眠くなったら寝る
If I get sleepy, I sleep.
お昼過ぎに起きる
I wake up past noon.
遊びたくて遊ぶ
I play because I want to play.
お腹減ったらご飯を食べる
If I get hungry, I eat food.
嬉しかったら笑う
If I'm happy, I laugh.
悲しかったら泣いてもいいじゃない
If I'm sad, it's okay to cry, right?
明日の私のために
For the sake of tomorrow's me,
今日もなんとか頑張るのさ
I'll somehow do my best today too.
明日も頑張らなくていいように
So that I don't have to work hard tomorrow...
頑張るのさ
...I'll work hard now.
怠惰じゃないやこれ多分そうだ
This isn't laziness, this is probably it.
なんやでやることやっています
I'm somehow doing what I need to do.
What? Eh what?
誰に知られなくたって別にいいから
I don't really care if nobody knows.
私は私のマイルール
I follow my own rules.
明日楽するためにはハイチーズ
To take it easy tomorrow, say cheese!
意外とこんな感じでラブアンドピースのある
Surprisingly, with this kind of Love & Peace...
毎日を生きていたいのす
...I want to live every day.
Don't be Don't be 飛びしたいと
Don't be, don't be, I want to fly.
時々ドキッとしたい
I want my heart to pound sometimes.
Let me Let me Let me shine
明日天気になれ
May the weather be good tomorrow.
To be To be To be excite
To be, to be, to be excited!
心もっと踊りたい
I want my heart to dance more.
Sunday Monday Tuesday Wednesday
木金土日 Get!
Thu, Fri, Sat, Sun, Get!
辛くなったら歌う
If it gets tough, I sing.
むかついたら愚痴る
If I get annoyed, I complain.
やりたいようにやる
I do what I want.
それができたら苦労しないわ
If I could do that, I wouldn't struggle!
常に
Always,
一喜一憂
ups and downs.
してりゃ何かやろうと思ったんから
I figured I'd do something if I felt like it.
適当にセーブしてディスクは回収
Save appropriately and recover the disc.
でも頑張るのさ
But I'll do my best.
適当にとはまでは言わんが
I won't say 'half-heartedly'...
まあ頑張るのさ
...but, well, I'll do my best.
夢の中では
In my dreams,
ずーっとぐーたらしてやるんだ
I'm going to slack off forever!
誰かのためとかそんなんじゃなく
Not for someone else or anything like that,
明日の私のた め
but for tomorrow's me!
Fight!
楽するために苦しいことも乗り越えちゃうんだからね
I'll overcome painful things just to take it easy!
Fight!
やりたくないことやらないために
To avoid doing things I don't want to do,
やりたくないことやる
I do things I don't want to do!
Fight!
あれ？これって結局頑張れてる私
Huh? Doesn't this mean I'm working hard in the end?
とっても偉いじゃないか
Aren't I super amazing?!
自分時間堕落タイム確保
Securing my own time, my slacking time.
5時9時を死守しますと
I will defend my 5-to-9.
さらに愛や恋や舞いも忘れずに
Without forgetting love, romance, or dancing.
とどのつまり
In the end...
オーバーワークは立ち入り禁止ですよ
Overwork is strictly prohibited!
って注意喚起もしてますよ
I'm even issuing warnings about it!
ねえ楽して上手くして
Hey, taking it easy, doing it skillfully...
生きてくって難しいな
...living like that is tough, huh.
だって安定 裏技 一夜漬け
Because stability, cheat codes, overnight cramming...
甘い蜜には罠がある
...sweet nectar always has a trap.
イヤ！
No!
眠くなったら寝る
If I get sleepy, I sleep.
お昼過ぎに起きる
I wake up past noon.
遊びたくて遊ぶ
I play because I want to play.
お腹減ったらご飯を食べる
If I get hungry, I eat food.
嬉しかったら笑う
If I'm happy, I laugh.
悲しかったら泣いてもいいじゃない
If I'm sad, it's okay to cry, right?
明日の私のために
For the sake of tomorrow's me,
今日もなんとか頑張るのさ
I'll somehow do my best today too.
明日も頑張らなくていいように
So that I don't have to work hard tomorrow...
頑張るのさ
...I'll work hard now.
半端ないパッパラッパッパラッパラ
It's insane, pa-pa-ra pa-pa-ra pa-pa-ra!
Hey!
限界突破ラッパッパラッパッパラ
Breaking limits, pa-pa-ra pa-pa-ra!
Hey!
毎日半端ないパッパラッパッパラッパラ
Every day is insane, pa-pa-ra pa-pa-ra pa-pa-ra!
Hey!
限界突破ラッパッパラッパッパラ
Breaking limits, pa-pa-ra pa-pa-ra!
踊る暇があったら発明して
If you have time to dance, invent something.
歌う暇があったら発明して
If you have time to sing, invent something.
ライブのブッキング蹴って発明して
Reject the live booking and invent something.
そんな発明王にオレはなる
I'll become such an Invention King.
踊る暇があったら発明して
If you have time to dance, invent something.
歌う暇があったら発明して
If you have time to sing, invent something.
ライブのブッキング蹴って発明して
Reject the live booking and invent something.
そんな発明王にオレはなる
I'll become such an Invention King.
踊るエジソン
Dancing Edison,
自尊心
Self-esteem.
歌うエジソン
Singing Edison,
自尊心
Self-esteem.
踊るエジソン
Dancing Edison,
自尊心
Self-esteem.
歌うエジソン
Singing Edison,
自尊心
Self-esteem.
幼少期の頃から家で聴いてた音楽はハウスミュージック
Music I listened to at home since childhood was House Music.
サブスクのプレイリスト聴いて曲ディグったならクラブでDJ
Digging for songs on subscription playlists, then DJing at the club.
パソコン開いたならDTM
If I open the laptop, it's DTM.
ソフトはAbleton Live
The software is Ableton Live.
サークルでの宴会芸
Party tricks at the club circle.
ノリで始めたバンドで
With a band started on a whim.
まぐれでバズってメジャーデビュー
Went viral by a fluke and made a major debut.
なぜか今自信がないミュージシャン
Somehow now a musician with no confidence.
踊るエジソン 自尊心
Dancing Edison, self-esteem.
歌うエジソン 自尊心
Singing Edison, self-esteem.
踊るエジソン 自尊心
Dancing Edison, self-esteem.
歌うエジソン 自尊心
Singing Edison, self-esteem.
YouTubeを見て得る1%のひらめきインスピレーション
The 1% flash of inspiration gained from watching YouTube.
SNS通して繋がる発明家のコミュニケーション
Inventor's communication connecting through SNS.
インスタ映え狙った投稿 webニュースで情報収集
Posts aiming to be Insta-worthy, gathering info via web news.
間違いなくこれからの時代来るのは活動写真
Undoubtedly what's coming in the future is motion pictures.
いやー絶対来ると思うんだけどなー
Man, I definitely think it's coming though.
踊る暇があったら発明して
If you have time to dance, invent something.
歌う暇があったら発明して
If you have time to sing, invent something.
ライブのブッキング蹴って発明して
Kick the live booking and invent something.
そんな発明王にオレはなる
I'm gonna become that kind of King of Invention.
踊るエジソン 自尊心
Dancing Edison, self-esteem.
歌うエジソン 自尊心
Singing Edison, self-esteem.
踊るエジソン 自尊心
Dancing Edison, self-esteem.
歌うエジソン 自尊心
Singing Edison, self-esteem.
今日はこのままさよならじゃないよ
Today isn't goodbye just like this.
手をとってくれたなら
If you take my hand...
秘密も眠りにつくような夜に
On a night where even secrets fall asleep,
君を連れていくよ
I'll take you with me.
それは例えば遠く離れていたって
Even if, for example, we were far apart,
手を繋いでられるような
Like being able to hold hands.
奇跡のような
Like a miracle.
話をしよう
Let's talk.
窓は開けておいて
Keep the window open.
今日までを思い出して
Remembering everything up to today.
一つ一つ並べたら
If we line them up one by one,
明日の雨が気になりだして
Starting to worry about tomorrow's rain.
どうも眠れないみたいだ
Seem unable to sleep somehow.
変わりたくないことや
Things I don't want to change,
変わらなきゃいけないことも
And things I have to change.
少し忘れたまま
While forgetting them a little,
窓の外を眺めていたんだ
I was gazing out the window.
ああ雨が降り出すその前に
Ah, before the rain starts falling,
君のところまで行けるような気がして
I feel like I can make it to where you are.
目を閉じた
I closed my eyes.
そしてこのまま遠へと行こう
And let's go far away just like this.
手をとってくれるかな
Will you take my hand?
秘密も眠りにつくような夜を
A night where even secrets fall asleep,
君と泳いでくよ
I'll swim through it with you.
街の明かりが消える度に笑って
Laughing every time the city lights go out.
路地裏で抱き合おう
Let's embrace in the back alley.
馬鹿みたいな
Like idiots.
話をしよう
Let's talk.
窓は開けておいて
Keep the window open.
聞こえる？
Can you hear it?
聞こえる
I can hear it.
愛おしいことや無くせないものを
Precious things and things I can't lose...
教えてくれたのは今日みたいな
What taught me those was a day like today.
夜を重ねて織り上げてきた私たちに響く音
The sound echoing to us who have woven nights together.
夜が来るたびに心が踊ってしまうのは
The reason my heart dances every time night comes is...
また一つ重なっていくから
Because they stack up one by one again.
目を閉じてみたんだ
I tried closing my eyes.
今夜私たちだけで眠ろう
Let's sleep, just the two of us tonight.
誰にも言わないで
Don't tell anyone.
君が眠りにつくその少し前に
Just a little before you fall asleep...
名前を呼んで
...call my name.
叶わない願いに胸は痛んで
My chest hurts from a wish that won't come true,
うつむいてしまうけど
and I end up looking down, but...
誰もいない街へ誘いにゆくから
...I'll come to invite you to a town where no one is.
今日はこのままさよならじゃないよ
It's not goodbye like this today.
手をとってくれたなら
If you take my hand,
秘密も眠りにつくような夜に
on a night where even secrets fall asleep...
君を連れていくよ
...I'll take you with me.
それは例えば遠く離れてたって
Even if we were far apart, for example,
手を繋いでられるような奇跡のような
like a miracle where we can still hold hands...
話をしよう
...let's talk.
窓は開けておいて
Leave the window open.
聞こえる
Can you hear it?
愛おしいことや、無くせないものを
About precious things, and things we can't lose.
教えてくれたのは
What taught me that...
今日みたいな
...was a night like today.
夜を重ねて
Piling up the nights...
織り上げてきた私たちに
...for us who have woven them together.
響く音
The sound that resonates.
響く言葉
The words that resonate.
はい ということで
Okay, so...
皆さん 今回のライブ
everyone, for this live concert,
なんと新衣装が パパパパパッ ポポー
a new outfit is... Pa-pa-pa-pa-po-po!
ありましたー
Here it is!
ということで あの びっくりしたかな
So, were you surprised?
びっくりしたんじゃないかなと思います
I bet you were surprised.
あの こちらね すごいあの
Um, this one, you see...
煌びやかな衣装となっているんですけど
...is a very gorgeous outfit.
ちょっと今 スクショ
Right now, screenshots...
どう？撮る？
How about it? Want to take some?
えーい
Yay!
可愛いですか？
Is it cute?
ぜひ あのハッシュタグでね
Please, use the hashtag...
あの ぜひ呟いてください
...and tweet about it.
可愛いでしょう
It's cute, right?
何やらね この後ちょっと衣装のね いろいろ
Somehow, after this, there's various things about the outfit...
細部までちょっと見る機会がありそうな予感がするので
I have a feeling there will be a chance to see the details later...
いったんね スクショだけお願いします
...so just the screenshots for now, please.
そして あとこちらね
Also, look at this...
見て
Look.
手首にプラプラって紐があるんだけど
There are strings dangling from my wrists,
これね 取れます
but these can be removed.
じゃあ取ってもらおうかな
Shall we have them removed?
えい！えい！ということで
Ei! Ei! And just like that...
はい 取れます
Yes, they come off.
そう こちらバージョンもスクショ撮ってもらおう
So, let's take screenshots of this version too.
えーい
Yay!
可愛いですか？
Is it cute?
ぴゃあー
Pyaa!
ね すごい可愛らしい衣装
Right? It's such a cute outfit.
え ちょっとね あのドキドキするんですが
I'm getting a little heart-pounding nervous, but...
んー いや何か
Hmm, well...
でもちょっと一人寂しいな
but being alone is a bit lonely.
何か... 団員さん... ん？
Something... Dain-san... Hmm?
あ！ありゃ可愛いね！
Ah! Oh my, how cute!
おお 何かムズムズしてる おお どうしたどうした
Oh, he's wiggling around. What's wrong?
くわー！
Whoa!
団員さん飛んできた！
Dain-san flew over!
そんなに え？ ノエちゃんに会いたかったんかな？
That much, huh? Did you want to see Noe-chan?
可愛いね
You're cute.
いっぱいスクショ撮れた？んー
Did you get lots of screenshots? Hmm.
団員さんとのツーショット！
A two-shot with Dain-san!
可愛い... え 何々？
Cute... Eh, what is it?
あ 今日は安眠テーマで
Ah, today's theme is peaceful sleep...
あ 心地が良い... あ なるほどね
Ah, it's comfortable... I see.
ん？曲のリクエスト？
Hm? A song request?
あ 子守唄みたいな曲が聴きたい
Ah, you want to hear a lullaby-like song.
あ そうなの団員さん
Ah, is that so, Dain-san?
じゃあせっかくね 団員さん来てくれたし 一緒にじゃあ子守唄
Well, since you're here, let's do a lullaby together.
うん 歌うよ歌う だからちょっとついて来て
Yeah, I'll sing, I'll sing. So come along.
一緒に行くよ ほら おいで！
Let's go together. Come on, come here!
小さな人の子よ
Oh little child of man,
森へ迷い込んだ
you've wandered into the forest.
大きな
A big...
ぼうやは見えないのね
You can't see anything, can you, little boy?
なにも知らない
Knowing nothing,
まぁるいほっぺたよ
With your round cheeks.
ねむれやねむれ
Sleep, oh sleep.
しずかな水辺においで
Come to the quiet waterside.
ぼうやの夢は
The little boy's dream is...
竜の背に運ばれて
Carried on a dragon's back,
山の向こうへ消える
Disappearing beyond the mountains.
よろずの子らも
All the children of the world,
ならんでねむる
Sleep side by side.
七つ数えたら
If you count to seven,
なかよくねむってく
We'll drift off to sleep together.
なにも見えない
Seeing nothing,
小さなおめめだよ
With your little eyes.
ねむれやねむれ
Sleep, oh sleep.
そよぐ草むらへおいで
Come to the rustling grass.
ぼうやの夢は
The little boy's dream is...
母さんを探しては
Searching for mother,
空の向こうへ帰る
Returning beyond the sky.
竜の背に運ばれて
Carried on a dragon's back,
山の向こうへ消える
Disappearing beyond the mountains.
夕月夜 顔だす
The evening moon peeks out,
消えてく 子供の声
The fading voices of children.
遠く遠く
Far, far away,
この空のどこかに
Somewhere in this sky,
君はいるんだろう
You must be there.
夏の終わりに 2人で抜け出した
At the end of summer, the two of us slipped away,
この公園で見つけた
And found in this park,
あの星座
That constellation...
何だか 覚えてる？
Do you remember what it was?
会えなくても 記憶をたどって
Even if we can't meet, tracing my memories,
同じ幸せを見たいんだ
I want to see the same happiness.
あの香りとともに
Along with that scent,
花火がぱっと開く
Fireworks burst open.
行きたいよ 君のところへ
I want to go to where you are.
今すぐ かけだして 行きたいよ
I want to run out right now and go.
まっ暗で何も見えない
In the pitch black, I can't see anything,
怖くても大丈夫
But even if I'm scared, it's okay.
数えきれない星空が
Countless stars in the sky,
今もずっとここにあるんだよ
Are still right here, always.
泣かないよ
I won't cry.
あの道まで響く靴の音が耳に
The sound of shoes echoing down to that road remains in my ears.
残る大きな自分の影を見つめて思うのでしょう
I gaze at my own large shadow left behind, and I suppose I think...
ちっとも変わらないはずなのに
Even though nothing should have changed at all...
せつない気持ちふくらんでく
this painful feeling just keeps swelling up.
どんなに想ったって君はもういない
No matter how much I think of you, you're no longer here.
行きたいよ 君のそばに
I want to go to where you are.
小さくても1番に君が好きだよ
Even if it's small, I love you the most.
強くいられる
I can stay strong.
願いを流れ星にそっと唱えてみたけれど
I tried softly whispering my wish to a shooting star, but...
泣かないよ 届くだろう きれいな空に
I won't cry. Surely it will reach this beautiful sky.
会えなくても記憶をたどって
Even if we can't meet, I trace my memories.
同じ幸せを見たいんだ
I want to see the same happiness.
あの香りとともに花火がぱっと開く
Along with that scent, the fireworks burst open.
行きたいよ 君のところへ
I want to go to your side.
小さな手を握りしめて
Clasping my small hands tight.
泣きたいよ それはそれはきれいな空だった
I want to cry. It was, it was such a beautiful sky.
願いを流れ星にそっと唱えてみたけれど
I tried softly whispering my wish to a shooting star, but...
泣きたいよ 届かない想いをこの空に
I want to cry. Sending my unreachable feelings to this sky.
もう何十回も
Already dozens of times...
もう何百回も
already hundreds of times...
霞む空見上げて
looking up at the hazy sky.
辿り着いた場所が
The place I finally reached...
運命のダイヤモンド
is the diamond of destiny.
何千回も
Thousands of times...
もう何万回も
already tens of thousands of times...
涙流した君へ
to you, who shed tears.
ねぇ 諦められた
Hey, was there ever a time...
ことはあったっけ？
that you could just give up?
「憧れ＝限界」だから
Because 'Admiration = Limit'...
もういらないよ
I don't need it anymore.
そこに留まるなんて
To just stay there...
もったいないでしょ
is a waste, isn't it?
それぞれの物語
Each of our stories...
交差する瞬間を
the moment they intersect...
見つめる意味は
the meaning of gazing at it is...
放った夢だけ
Only the dreams released...
大きな弧を描いて
draw a large arc.
はち切れそうな 煌めきを
The bursting sparkle...
消えることなく
without ever fading...
どこまででも
anywhere and everywhere.
世界の向こうに 届けよう
Let's send it beyond the world.
終わることのない この胸の衝動は
This impulse in my heart that never ends...
どうしたって どうしても ぼくを呼んでいた
No matter what, no matter what, it was calling me.
だから
So...
その先へと 走り続ける
I'll keep running towards what lies ahead.
次へ 次へ
To the next stage, to the next!
妄想だった？ 中途半端な
Was it a delusion? Half-hearted...
概念さ 抱えて立ち尽くしていた
...concepts, I stood there holding onto them.
通り雨はプレリュード
The passing rain is a prelude.
何千回も 何万回も 挑み続けたきみへ
To you who continued to challenge thousands, tens of thousands of times.
ねぇ聴かせてよ 夢は叶うんだって
Hey, tell me that dreams do come true.
「諦め=完敗」ならば
If 'giving up equals total defeat'...
絶対にないよ
...then there's absolutely no way.
だれに邪魔されようと
No matter who gets in my way.
ためらわないで
Don't hesitate.
託された情熱を 落とさずに繋いでく
Connecting the entrusted passion without dropping it.
そう最後まで
Yes, until the very end.
フラッグに誓い 雄々しくはためいて
Vow to the flag, fluttering bravely.
鳴り止まないファンファーレ
The fanfare that won't stop ringing.
いつも心に 流れていた
It was always flowing in my heart.
遠い未来へ 祈るよう
Like praying to the distant future.
忘れられない あの日の後悔を
The unforgettable regrets of that day...
追いかけて 追いかけて 滑り込んだ この想い
...chasing, chasing, I slid into this feeling.
青いソラに ふと溢れてった
Suddenly overflowing into the blue sky.
遠く 遠く
Far away, far away.
終わらない 終わらない
It doesn't end, it doesn't end.
仕事が山積み終わらない
The pile of work doesn't end.
止まらない 止まらない
It doesn't stop, it doesn't stop.
それでも時間は止まらない
Even so, time doesn't stop.
ヘトヘト 溜まり溜まったヘイト
Exhausted, piled up hate.
全伐 誓いズバット コンボ 名手に金属バット
Vowing total punishment, Zubat combo, a metal bat to the expert.
仕事手一杯 今日も手一杯
My hands are full with work, hands full again today.
No more 無知
No more ignorance.
Gimme Gimme 重視
Gimme Gimme priority.
I see
奔走 Anytime 奔走 Anytime
Running around anytime, running around anytime.
羽目外れそうで MPすっからかん
About to lose control, my MP is empty.
自分自身に厳しすぎちゃう
I'm too strict with myself.
すぐさまヘラヘラ優等生
Immediately becoming a grinning honor student.
さっぱり足りない柔軟性
Completely lacking flexibility.
自分自身としっかり向き合う
Facing myself properly.
一番必要なものは
The most important thing is...
トレビアン
Très Bien.
ご褒美ちょうだい
Give me a reward.
天手古舞うようなリズムにバイバイしちゃえ
Say bye-bye to this chaotic rhythm.
ドレミファの音に Go Round
Go Round on the Do-Re-Mi-Fa notes.
ぎゅうぎゅう詰め込んだメロディ どんどんフリーダム
Crammed melody, rapidly freedom.
好きなもの食べ放題
All-you-can-eat of what I like.
オキシトシン増す脳内
Oxytocin increasing in my brain.
ほらもっともっとちょうだい
Come on, give me more and more.
膨大
Enormous.
Get Ready
サボです たまに空振り
It's skipping, sometimes swinging and missing.
ミスした日こそ胸張り大盛り
On days I miss, I stick out my chest, large serving.
要らない まやかしの甘やかし
I don't need fake pampering.
ハッピーになるため歌おう 高らかに
Let's sing loudly to become happy.
自分自身がやっぱり一番
Myself is number one after all.
理性と欲望が平行線
Reason and desire are parallel lines.
望みは幸せエンドレス
My wish is endless happiness.
自分自身としっかり付き合う
Properly getting along with myself.
我慢は体に毒だよ
Endurance is poison for the body.
トレビアン
Très Bien.
ご褒美ちょうだい
Give me a reward.
天手古舞うようなリズムにバイバイしちゃえ
Say bye-bye to this chaotic rhythm.
ドレミファの音に Go Round
Go Round on the Do-Re-Mi-Fa notes.
ぎゅうぎゅう詰め込んだメロディ どんどんフリーダム
Crammed melody, rapidly freedom.
1, 2の3 はい
One, two, three, yes!
窮屈な鬱屈に 疲弊ヤストレス
Cramped gloom, exhaustion and stress.
状態異常警報から解放
Release from the status abnormality alarm.
本日は欲望開放パーリナイ
Today is a desire-liberation party night!
乾杯！
Cheers!
それに横暴 褒美 頂戴
Give me tyranny and rewards too.
てんてこ舞いのようなリズムに
To this chaotic rhythm,
バイバイしちゃえ
just say bye-bye!
どれに反応 本能 導入 到来
Which reaction? Instinct, introduction, arrival.
ぎゅっぎゅっ 詰め込め
Tight, tight, pack it in,
どんどん繰り出す
dish it out more and more.
Freedom
ぎゅっぎゅっ 夢の国
Tight, tight, in the land of dreams,
本気 どんどん 好きになる
for real, falling more and more in love.
フィーバー！
Fever!
輝夜の城で踊りたい
I want to dance in Kaguya's castle.
おいで！おいで！
Come on! Come on!
誘惑のDance again
A tempting Dance again.
おいでよ おいで！
Come here! Come on!
輝夜の城へ
To Kaguya's castle.
出逢いがあやつるミステリー
A mystery manipulated by our meeting.
危険なペルソナ
A dangerous persona.
踊ろう！踊ろう！
Let's dance! Let's dance!
終わらないDance beat
The never-ending Dance beat.
踊ろうよ 踊ろう！
Come dance! Let's dance!
輝夜の城で
In Kaguya's castle.
夜空を切り取るレーザービーム
Laser beams cutting through the night sky.
私と見てよ？
Will you watch them with me?
まばゆい星が照らす想い
Feelings illuminated by the dazzling stars.
今宵の夢よ永遠に
May tonight's dream last forever.
明日のことは
Everything about tomorrow...
忘れたいの
I want to forget.
にこ！
Nico!
私は紅い薔薇の姫よ
I am the crimson rose princess.
優しくさらわれたい
I want to be swept away gently.
そっと囁いて
Whisper softly,
意味ありげに目をそらす
and look away suggestively.
あなたは白い月の騎士
You are the white moon knight.
触れた手がまだ熱い
The hand that touched me is still hot.
のがさずに
Don't let me go,
抱きしめて
hold me tight.
この奇跡を恋と呼ぶのね
I suppose this miracle is what you call love.
おいで！おいで！
Come on! Come on!
情熱でDance again
Dance again with passion.
おいでよ おいで！
Come here! Come on!
輝夜の城へ
To Kaguya's castle.
迷いを飲み込むエナジー
Energy that swallows all hesitation.
眠らぬパッショネイト
A sleepless passionate night.
踊ろう！踊ろう！
Let's dance! Let's dance!
止まらないDance beat
The unstoppable Dance beat.
踊ろうよ 踊ろう！
Come dance! Let's dance!
輝夜の城で
In Kaguya's castle.
星座が織りなすディスコティーク
A discotheque woven by the constellations.
私も混ぜて？
Won't you include me too?
きらめく星に誓う心
A heart swearing to the twinkling stars.
儚い夢でいいわ
I don't mind if it's a fleeting dream.
明日は
Tomorrow...
明日の
tomorrow's...
風が吹くの
wind will blow.
だよね！
Right!
私は黒い薔薇の姫よ
I am the black rose princess.
激しくさらわれたい
I want to be swept away violently.
だから微笑んで
So smile for me,
追いかけてと目が誘う
and your eyes invite me to chase you.
あなたも黒い月の騎士
You are the black moon knight too.
瞳の奥は熱い
Deep in your eyes, it's hot.
つかまえて
Catch me,
抱きしめて
hold me tight.
この奇跡は恋を
This miracle calls for...
呼ぶのね
love, doesn't it?
一緒にいこう？
Shall we go together?
俯いてるの？
Are you looking down?
他の人見ちゃイヤ！
Don't look at anyone else!
私だけを見て
Look only at me.
後悔するわよ
You're going to regret it.
楽しも！
Let's have fun!
早くしなさいよ
Hurry it up already.
鈍いのですね
You're quite dense, aren't you?
いいの？
Is that okay?
私は紅い
I am the crimson...
薔薇の姫よ
rose princess.
優しくさらわれたい
I want to be swept away gently.
そっと囁いて
Whisper softly,
意味ありげに目をそらす
and look away suggestively.
あなたは白い
You are the white...
月の騎士
moon knight.
触れた手がまだ熱い
The hand that touched me is still hot.
のがさずに
Don't let me go,
抱きしめて
hold me tight.
この奇跡を恋と
I suppose this miracle...
呼ぶのね
is what you call love.
はぁ…はぁ…
Haa... haa...
ということで、3期生のみんなと『輝夜の城で踊りたい』を歌って踊りましたー！
So, I sang and danced 'I Want to Dance at Kaguya's Castle' with everyone from Gen 3!
イェーイ！
Yay!
団長、お誕生日…
Danchou, happy...
おめでとう！
Birthday!
ありがとうー！
Thank you!
ちょっと可愛いいんじゃない？
Wait, isn't that kinda cute?
はーい！
Yes!
え、可愛い？
Eh, cute?
動きがちょっと…
The movement is a bit...
ちょっとね、あの…
Just a bit, um...
ぶりっ子な…
Acting all cutesy...
はい！
Yes!
可愛いですか？
Is it cute?
あー、可愛い！
Ah, it's cute!
すごいね、なんかここがめっちゃ迫ってくる
Wow, this part is really coming at me.
ここ大丈夫ですか？
Is this part okay?
おっぱいがお尻だよ、ノエルちゃん
Your boobs look like a butt, Noel-chan.
女のおっぱいに挨拶しちゃう…
Greeting a woman's boobs...
今日からはさ、こう話せばいいのかな？
Starting today, maybe I should talk like this?
違う違う！
No, no!
全然違う！
Totally different!
そんなキャラじゃないだろ！
That's not your character!
えっと、今回のね衣装はね…
Um, so for this outfit...
あの200万人の記念で、はい！作って頂きました！
It was made to commemorate reaching 2 million subscribers!
他にも変わったところ、今日のライブからであるんだけど…
There's something else that changed starting from today's live too...
あれ？マリンが怒ってる？
Huh? Is Marine angry?
え、あれ？あ！
Eh, huh? Ah!
キャーー！
Kyaaa!
え、気づいた？
Eh, did you notice?
当たり前だろ！
Of course we did!
そうなんですよ、ちょっとメイク変わりました！
That's right, my makeup changed a bit!
全然違う！
It's totally different!
全然違うじゃん！
It's completely different!
なんか可愛いー！
It's kinda cute!
いいじゃん！
It's nice!
ちなみに、お気に入りの顔がありましてね…
By the way, I have a favorite expression...
ちょっとね、あの…お困り顔がね…
Just a bit, um... the troubled face...
そう、可愛いですこれ。
Yes, this is cute.
お口がね、プリンってなってるんです。
My mouth goes all 'purin' (pouty).
あ、本当だ、プリンだ！
Ah, it's true, it is pouty!
食べちゃうぞ！
I'm gonna eat you!
うわぁー！
Whoa!
ペコちゃん助けてー！
Peko-chan help me!
あ、そうか、バーチャルだった。
Ah, right, it was virtual.
え、じゃあちょっと衣装せっかくなんでね。
Well then, since we have the new outfit...
あ、そうだね！
Ah, that's right!
下からちょっと、舐めるように行きましょうよ、靴から見ましょ、靴から！
Let's go from the bottom up, licking it with our eyes. Let's look from the shoes!
あら可愛いお靴！
Oh my, what cute shoes!
ちょっとよく見して！
Let me see them properly!
ヒールなのね！
So they're heels!
あら、可愛い！
Oh, cute!
リボンついてる！
There's a ribbon attached!
普段はね、通常でぺったんこだから、ちょっと身長盛りました。
Usually, my normal outfit has flats, so I added a little height.
リボン2個構え！後ろにね！
Double ribbon stance! On the back too!
そうなんです。
That's right.
えー可愛い！
Eeh, cute!
いい！いい！いい！じゃちょっと舐めるように…
Good! Good! Good! Now let's go up like we're licking...
うう〜〜〜！
Uuugh~~~~!
一体どんなおパンツ…
What kind of panties are...
あれ！？
Huh!?
パンツ…！
Panties...!
なんか変態が…
There's a pervert...
好奇心が！
My curiosity!
えー、こんな感じで。
Umm, it looks like this.
あ、ちょっとそんな、ささっと終わんないで！
Ah, hey, don't finish so quickly!
まだ舐めてる最中！舐めてる最中！
I'm still licking! I'm still licking!
あーーーーっ！
Aaaaaaaah!
ここ、ノエルがいてね！
Look here, there's 'Noel' written!
あ！ノエルって書いてる！
Ah! It says Noel!
ノエルじゃなくてね！
Not Noel (the name)!
ノエルちゃん！
Noel-chan!
ここ！
Here!
皆さんご覧ください！
Everyone, look at this!
ここの、この、この、この、この胸、この、この、この隙間！隙間！隙間！
This, this, this, this chest, this, this, this gap! Gap! Gap!
分かります？
Do you understand?
この下の、乳と乳の間の…
This space underneath, between the boobs...
本当だ、すごいね！
It's true, amazing!
そこ、なってる！
It's shaped like that!
隙間がね！
That gap!
ほら！
Look!
うわーーーー！
Whoa~~~~!
大丈夫！？
Are you okay!?
どこが大丈夫！？
What part is okay!?
どこか？
Somewhere?
最高の衣装！
Best outfit ever!
じゃあ、ちょっと上を見せるにあたって…
So, to show the upper part...
このね、ひらひら取れるからちょっと…
These frills can be removed, so just...
あ、可愛いそのひらひら！
Ah, those frills are cute!
あ、取ってみて、取ってみて！
Ah, take them off, take them off!
はい！
Okay!
取ってください！
Please take them off!
あ、取った！
Ah, they're off!
おおー！見やすい！
Ooh! It's easier to see!
そう、見やすい！
Yes, easier to see!
バンザーイ！
Banzai!
え、横どうなってるのかしら？
Eh, I wonder how the side looks?
え、なんかすごいね！
Eh, it's kinda amazing!
ゆっくりクルクル回って！
Spin around slowly!
クルクルクルクル〜
Spin, spin, spin~
髪可愛い！
Your hair is cute!
髪の毛ふわふわで可愛い！
Your hair is fluffy and cute!
ふわふわだよー！
It's so fluffy!
三つ編みめちゃ可愛い！
The braids are super cute!
お姫様！
A princess!
なんかすごいリボンがこう、髪にね、こう巻き込んである感じで…
It feels like the ribbon is, like, woven into the hair...
そうなのよ。
That's right.
編み込んで！
Braided in!
ペコラちゃんも言ってたけど…
Pekora-chan said it too, but...
えー可愛いー！
Eeh, cute!
姫騎士なんでね！
I'm a Princess Knight, after all!
お姫様！
Princess!
似合ってます！
It suits you!
可愛すぎる！
Too cute!
こんなの好きになっちゃう…ちょっとカエル化したいから、ちょっといつもの動きして！
I'm gonna fall for this... I wanna turn back into a frog (get over it), so do your usual moves!
待ってた！待ってた！
I was waiting for that! Waiting for that!
あ！
Ah!
あーなんか、好きじゃなくなった。
Ah, somehow, I don't like it anymore.
凪いだ！
It calmed down!
あぶねー！
That was close!
恋するとこだった！
I almost fell in love!
いや、でも本当に、可愛い衣装本当…
No, but really, this cute outfit is truly...
え、超可愛い！
Eh, super cute!
ありがとうー！
Thank you!
おめでとう！
Congratulations!
いいかもマジで！
It might be really good!
超可愛い！
Super cute!
いやでもさ、みんなさ…
No but, everyone...
今回はね、その団長の新衣装お披露目だったから、ま、みんなにはちょっとアイドル衣装だったんですけど…
This time it was the reveal of Danchou's new outfit, so everyone else wore idol outfits, but...
うんうん！
Yeah, yeah!
みんなもさ、衣装持ってるじゃん！
You guys have outfits too, right!
お！
Oh!
そうなんだよね！
That's right!
なんか、並んだりとかも今後したいなー！
I wanna line up with you all in the future!
え、絶対野望！
Eh, that's definitely an ambition!
野望！野望！
Ambition! Ambition!
てか3Dで、また歌って踊りたいなー！
I mean, I want to sing and dance in 3D again!
え、ちょっとそれ…え…！？
Eh, wait, that's... eh...!?
え、まさか！？
Eh, no way!?
おやおや！？
Oya oya!?
全然分かんないして！
Act like you don't know at all!
あったかなー！？
Was there something like that!?
あったこと、ないよー！？
I don't remember anything like that!?
はい！ということで、ここから大事なお知らせをたくさんしていきます！
Yes! So, from here on, I'll be making lots of important announcements!
お願いしまーす！
Please do!
まず、ホロライブ3期生の単独ライブ！
First, Hololive 3rd Generation's solo live!
ホロライブサードジェネレーションライブ、『キュルルン大作戦 最強アイドル推すしかないでしょ』！
Hololive 3rd Generation Live, 'Kyururun Grand Strategy: You Have No Choice But To Stan The Strongest Idols'!
開催決定しております！
It's been decided!
イェーイ！
Yay!
はい、日時ですが…
Yes, as for the date...
2026年1月の17日と18日の2日間に渡って開催されまーす！
It will be held over two days on January 17th and 18th, 2026!
いや、会場はね、あのでっかい…
And the venue is that huge...
そう、Kアリーナ横浜！
Yes, K-Arena Yokohama!
となってまーす！
That's the place!
おっきいー！
It's huge!
いや、昨日ね、なんと、まぁちょっと2次先行…
Actually, yesterday, well, the second lottery...
あ、ちょうどね！
Ah, just right!
終わっちゃったということなんですけど…
It ended, but...
なんかね、この後、まぁ先着の一般販売が、まぁ12月の14日とかの…
So, after this, well, general sales (first come) start on December 14th...
お昼の12時から…
From 12:00 PM...
勝ち取ってください
Please win it!
お願いします！
Please!
そして配信チケットはね、まだありますので
And streaming tickets are still available,
絶賛発売中ですので、よろしくお願いいたします！
so they are on sale now! Please check them out!
そして、まあこのライブを見てくださった方で...
And, for those watching this live...
まあ買い忘れてる人はいないと思うけど
I don't think anyone forgot to buy them, but...
あの、グッズのね、先行販売と受注販売も
Um, the goods pre-sale and made-to-order sales...
明日のね、えー、11月25日の18時までとなっております
are available until tomorrow, November 25th at 18:00.
明日ね！
Tomorrow!
そう！だから、あのライブ会場でペンライト振りたいとか
Right! So, if you want to wave a penlight at the venue,
配信見ながらペンライト振りたいよって人はぜひ
or wave one while watching the stream,
えー、この機会をお見逃しなく！
please don't miss this opportunity!
現地行く人は絶対あったほうが盛り上がりますよ！
Those going to the venue will definitely have more fun with it!
お願いします！
Please!
いやー楽しみだね
Man, I'm excited.
めっちゃ楽しみ！
Super excited!
そう、団長もね、ちょっとおめいくを変えたから
Yeah, Danchou changed her makeup a bit too.
かわいい！
Cute!
当日の楽しみ！
Looking forward to the day!
そんな感じで、せっかくね来てくれたから、意気込みを一言ちょっと
So, since you're all here, how about a quick word of ambition?
一言ね、聞こうかなと
Just a quick word.
誰から行くの？
Who's going first?
えーじゃあ、ちょっとマリンからこういう順番で
Uhh, then let's go in this order starting with Marine.
頑張るぞ！
I'll do my best!
楽しむぞ！
I'll enjoy it!
みんなで盛り上げるぞ！
Let's liven it up together!
あ、ありがとう...え？
Ah, thank you... Eh?
光の速さで去っていった... みんなありがとう！
They left at light speed... Thanks everyone!
てな感じで、えーここからはノエルちゃんの告知に行きます！
So with that, uh, I'll move on to Noel-chan's announcements!
えーまず一つ目はこちら！
Err, first up is this!
はい、今年も出ます！白銀ノエル誕生日記念2025のグッズー！
Yes, it's out this year too! Shirogane Noel Birthday Celebration 2025 Goods!
わーい！
Yay!
えー生誕グッズ、まずはこちら！
Err, birthday goods, first is this!
睡夢の世界へキラキラLEDアートパネル！
"To the World of Slumber" Sparkling LED Art Panel!
えーイラストは、みょんい先生が描いてくれました！
The illustration was drawn by MyungYi-sensei!
ありがとうございます！
Thank you very much!
今回のね、まあ生誕ライブのステージと、新衣装がテーマになっております。
The theme this time is the birthday live stage and the new outfit.
まあLEDということで、こちら光る！ということでね
Well, since it's LED, this lights up!
あの、ぜひお部屋に飾って、あの今回のライブを思い出して、
Please decorate your room with it and remember this live,
そう、思い出にしてください！
yes, make it a memory!
はい、そして次はこちら！
Okay, and next is this!
いろんなノエちゃんランダムマルチバンドー！
Various Noel-chan Random Multi-Bands!
ということで、まるえり先生が描いてくれました！
Marueri-sensei drew these for us!
いや、いろんなね、ノエちゃんがいますので
There are all kinds of Noel-chans,
まあちょっと、どのノエちゃんがね、おうちに来るかなーってちょっと楽しみにしつつ
so look forward to seeing which Noel-chan comes to your house.
届いたらね、まあマルチバンド、こちら
Once it arrives, well, this Multi-Band...
あの、お片付けの必需品となってます！
It's an essential item for tidying up!
ぜひね、あのコードまとめるときとか、はい、実用性に富んでますので
Please use it when organizing cords. It's very practical,
使ってみてください！
so give it a try!
次は、えーこちら！
Next is, uh, this!
はい、姫騎士ノエルぬいぐるみキーホルダー！
Yes, Princess Knight Noel Plushie Keychain!
昨年はね、あのサンタさんのノエちゃんがぬいぐるみとしてキーホルダー出たんですが
Last year, Santa Noel-chan was released as a plushie keychain,
今回は、せっかく新衣装が出たので、えーこちらでぬいぐるみキーホルダーを作りました！
but this time, since I have a new outfit, I made a plushie keychain with this look!
あの姫騎士として、団員さんを守りますので、
As a Princess Knight, I will protect all the Dan-in,
ぜひ肌身離さず、えー、持ってください！
so please keep me with you at all times!
えー次は、こちら！
Err, next is this!
はい、わんちょむ2wayネックピロー！
Yes, Wanchom 2-Way Neck Pillow!
まあ安眠にね、最適なネックピローなんですけど
It's the perfect neck pillow for a good sleep,
今回はなんと、ひっくり返すとわんちょむになっているということで
but this time, surprisingly, if you flip it inside out, it becomes Wanchom!
まあわんちょむはね、あの今年から団長のおうちにお迎えしたわんちゃんのことなんですけど
Wanchom is the doggie I welcomed into Danchou's home this year,
えーグッズにしちゃいました！
and I went ahead and made him into goods!
えーちょっとね、あのノエちゃんの、あい、私情が入ってますということで
Uh, well, there's a bit of Noel-chan's personal affection in this,
ぜひ団員さんのおうちにも迎えてください！
so please welcome him into your homes as well, Dan-in!
えー最後にフルセットを見てみましょう！こちら！
Err, finally, let's look at the Full Set! Here!
はい、今年もいっぱい、いっぱいグッズが出ました！
Yes, lots and lots of goods came out this year too!
いや、ぜひぜひ、あのゲットしてみてね
Please, definitely try to get them.
そしてこのね、全部のフルセット特典があります！
And there is a bonus for this entire Full Set!
それはこちら！
That is this!
はい、ということでフルセットを購入してくださった方に、チェキ風ブロマイドカード
Yes, so for those who purchase the Full Set, a Cheki-style Bromide Card
ついてきます！
is included!
いやとても素敵！
It's truly lovely!
通常バージョンは箔押しの複製サインが
The regular version comes with a foil-stamped reproduction signature.
えー数量限定バージョンは、団長の直筆サインがついてきます！
Err, the limited quantity version comes with Danchou's handwritten signature!
あの心を込めて書きますので
I will write them with all my heart,
ぜひゲットしてみてください！
so please try to get one!
さらにさらに、フルセットを購入してくれた方全員に
Furthermore, furthermore! For everyone who buys the Full Set,
特典ボイスもついてきちゃいます！
a bonus voice recording is also included!
フルセットのね、なんかちょっと欲しいって、みんな思ったんじゃないでしょうか
You all kinda want the Full Set now, don't you?
ぜひゲットしてみてください！
Please check it out!
よろしくお願いします。
Please check it out.
えー、生誕グッズは22時、カートオープンです。
The birthday goods cart will open at 10:00 PM.
皆さん、ぜひゲットしてください。お願いします。
Everyone, please make sure to get them. Thank you!
えー、さらにさらに！重大告知があります。
And furthermore! I have a major announcement.
なんとそれは... ズンズンズン...
And that is... *drumroll*...
はい！
Yes!
新曲があります！
I have a new song!
で、その新曲をね、発表するにあたって、
And, regarding the announcement of this new song,
なんと！
believe it or not!
なんかちょっと今回、スペシャルな方からね、コメントをちょっと頂いてるみたい...
It seems we've received a comment from a special someone this time...
なんだけど、え、誰なんだろう？ちょっとノエルちゃん分かんないな。
But, uh, who could it be? I actually don't know.
誰でしょうか？
Who is it?
え、待って！うわ、すっごいキラキラしてる！
Wait! Whoa, it's so sparkly!
こんまっする〜！
Kon-muscle!
えっ、ちょっと待って... うわ、こんまっする！
Eh, wait a minute... Whoa, Kon-muscle!
白銀ノエルさん、お誕生日おめでとうございます。
Shirogane Noel-san, happy birthday.
おめでとうございます... え、メジ...？
Thank you... Eh, Meji...?
そして団員の皆さん、配信を楽しんでいらっしゃいますか？
And to all the knights, are you enjoying the stream?
楽しんでますか？
Are you enjoying it?
大分県知事の佐藤樹一郎です。
I am the Governor of Oita Prefecture, Sato Kiichiro.
なにー！？
What!?
知事ー！？
The Governor!?
この度は、新曲の発表もおめでとうございます。
Congratulations on the announcement of your new song.
すごい！ありがとうございます。
Amazing! Thank you so much.
今回、私がノエルさんの新曲のタイトル発表を任せていただけることになりました。
I have been entrusted with announcing the title of Noel-san's new song.
してくれるんですか！？
You're going to do it!?
それでは早速、曲名を発表したいと思います。
So, without further ado, I would like to announce the song title.
お願いします！
Please!
その名も...
The title is...
『VAVAVA！バーチャル大分』
'VAVAVA! Virtual Oita'
バーチャル大分！わーい！
Virtual Oita! Yaaay!
えー、そうですね、『バーチャル大分』と入っていますので、
Well, since it includes 'Virtual Oita',
大分をバーチャルで楽しめるような歌なのかな？
I imagine it's a song where you can enjoy Oita virtually.
はい！そうです！
Yes! That's right!
はい！大分のオススメ、沢山ありますよ！
Yes! Oita has many recommendations!
あ、教えてくださってる。
Oh, he's telling us.
まずはなんと言っても温泉です！
First and foremost, it's the hot springs!
いや、温泉最高ですよね。
Yeah, hot springs are the best.
大分県は源泉数、湧出量ともに全国一位ですから。
Oita Prefecture is number one in Japan for both the number of sources and yield.
すごいんです。
It's amazing.
他にも、関アジや関サバ、かぼすブリ、大分和牛、唐揚げなんかの...
Also, Seki Aji, Seki Saba, Kabosu Buri, Oita Wagyu, Karaage...
あ、美味しい...
Ah, delicious...
食の魅力も満載ですね。
It's full of culinary charms too.
最高です。
It's the best.
ぜひ、皆さんにも味わっていただきたいです！
I'd love for everyone to taste them too!
うん！
Yeah!
はい！
Yes!
ノエルさん！大分を代表して応援しちょんけん！
Noel-san! We're cheering you on as a representative of Oita!
え、うわ、方言...
Eh, wow, the dialect...
これからも大分県PRを頼むけんな！
We're counting on you to keep promoting Oita Prefecture!
えっ！
Eh!
ありがとうございます！
Thank you so much!
新曲、真剣楽しみしちょんけん！
We're really looking forward to the new song!
はい！
Yes!
それでは、おつまっする〜！
Well then, Otsu-muscle!
おつ... おつまっする〜！
Otsu... Otsu-muscle!
あ、めじろんも！
Ah, Mejiron too!
めじ... おつまっする〜！おつまっする〜！
Meji... Otsu-muscle! Otsu-muscle!
ということで！わ、まさかの意外や意外！
So! Wow, that was totally unexpected!
大分県知事の佐藤樹一郎さんに、
From the Governor of Oita Prefecture, Sato Kiichiro-san,
新曲のタイトル発表と応援のコメントを頂きました！
we received the new song title announcement and a supportive comment!
ありがとうございます！
Thank you so much!
あの、これほんとに、あの、ノエルちゃんびっくりで、
Uhm, honestly, I'm just so surprised,
ほんとにこれ、サプライズなんですけど、
this really is a total surprise,
いや、ほんとにありがとうございます！
I mean, thank you so much!
まさか、こんな日が来るなんてっていうことで。
I never imagined a day like this would come.
いや、ほんとにすごい方から、あの、応援して頂いて嬉しいですね。
It's truly an honor to be cheered on by such an amazing person.
ちょ、団長ほんと何が起こったのか最初わからず...
Honestly, at first, I didn't even understand what was happening...
いや、しかもめじろんも横にいて、あのね...
And Mejiron was there next to him too, you know...
あの、緑の！そう、いましたね！
That green one! Yeah, it was there!
すごい可愛かったなと思います。
So cute.
あの、ほんとにね...
You know, really...
あの、ずっと、あの団長大分育ちで、はい、あの、大分の魅力を...
I've always... I grew up in Oita, so, yes, I've been sharing Oita's charm...
バーっと配信でね、あの、個人的に...
...on my streams, you know, just personally...
言ってるだけなんですけど、
Just talking about it on my own,
いや、ほんと日頃ね、大分の魅力を伝えてきてよかったなと思います。
but I'm really glad I've been conveying Oita's charm all this time.
あの、もちろん、これからも、あの、個人的...！
Um, of course, from now on too, personally...!
あの、特に何かおっきなことがあるわけではなく、
It's not like there's some huge deal happening,
あの、個人的に！
just personally!
はい、あの、団長、大分の魅力を、あの、伝えていきたいなと、
Yes, I want to keep conveying Oita's charm,
思いますので、皆さんも、
so everyone, please,
まだ大分行ったことない人は、
if you haven't been to Oita yet,
ぜひ大分行ってみてください！
definitely try visiting Oita!
いいところだよ〜！
It's a great place!
はい！ということで、あの、新曲歌っちゃいたいと思います。
Okay! So, with that, I want to sing the new song.
えー、聴いてください！
Please listen!
『VAVAVA！バーチャル大分』
'VAVAVA! Virtual Oita'
説明しよう！
Let me explain!
バーチャル大分とは、バーチャル九州の北東部に位置する広大な大地！
'Virtual Oita' is a vast land located in the northeast of Virtual Kyushu!
現実の大分県に限りなく近い、地上の楽園！
A paradise on earth, infinitely close to the real Oita Prefecture!
人はその地を、バーチャル大分と呼ぶ！
People call this land... Virtual Oita!
ババババ！バーチャル大分 世に放つ
VAVAVA! Virtual Oita, released to the world!
ババババ！バーチャル大分 湯を沸かす
VAVAVA! Virtual Oita, boiling the water!
君とバーチャル大分
Virtual Oita with you
駆け巡る
Run around
ババババ！バーチャル大分
VAVAVA! Virtual Oita
大分どーん！
Oita BOOM!
君は降り立つ
You touch down
魅惑の地獄の入り口
At the entrance of the enchanting Hell
絶えず湯が湧く
Hot water springs forth endlessly
誘惑の地
Land of temptation
海、かまど、白池、血の池
Umi, Kamado, Shiraike, Chinoike
鬼石坊主、鬼山
Oniishibozu, Oniyama
龍巻ぱーん！
Tatsumaki POP!
とり天、鶏めし、やせうま、だんご汁
Toriten, Chicken Rice, Yaseuma, Dango Soup
中津からあげ、冷麺
Nakatsu Karaage, Cold Noodles
関アジ、関サバ
Seki Aji, Seki Saba
かぼす、あつめし
Kabosu, Atsumeshi
まだまだ入るよ
I can still eat more!
鉄の胃袋 大魔神
Iron stomach, Great Majin
行こうぜ久住高原 湯煙の温泉
Let's go to Kuju Highlands, steamy hot springs
高崎山に
On Mount Takasaki,
金鱗湖
Lake Kinrin,
青の洞門
Ao no Domon,
斧戸・由布川渓谷
Onoto, Yufugawa Gorge,
進め 稲積水中鍾乳洞
Advance! Inazumi Underwater Limestone Cave!
果てしなき旅
An endless journey,
尽力遠足
an energetic excursion.
たどり着く先
The destination we reach,
食べる弁当
the bento we eat.
時空を超えた 奇跡の大地
A miraculous land transcending time and space!
バーチャル大分
Virtual Oita!
大分、行くぞー！
Oita, let's go!
バババ バーチャル大分 世に放つ
V-V-V-Virtual Oita, unleashed upon the world,
バババ バーチャル大分 湯を沸かす
V-V-V-Virtual Oita, boiling the water,
君とバーチャル大分 駆け巡る
Running around Virtual Oita with you.
バババ バーチャル大分 大分 ドーン！
V-V-V-Virtual Oita, Oita, BAM!
バーチャル大分 世に放つ
Virtual Oita, unleashed upon the world,
バーチャル大分 食べ尽くす
eating everything in Virtual Oita,
君とバーチャル大分 駆け巡る
running around Virtual Oita with you.
バババ バーチャル大分 大分 ドーン！
V-V-V-Virtual Oita, Oita, BAM!
大分 ドーン！
Oita, BAM!
よだきい しゃあしい えらしい
It's tiresome, noisy, lovely!
しんけん やおねぇ 風変わり
Seriously tough, eccentric!
なしか むげねぇ せせろしい
Why? Pitiful, bustling!
だけどあんた 今なにしちょん
But hey, what are you doing now?
説明しよう！
Let me explain!
バーチャル大分観光大使とは
The Virtual Oita Tourism Ambassador is...
バーチャル大分への深い郷土愛を持ち
...someone with a deep love for Virtual Oita...
その魅力を余すところなく伝え続ける存在
...who continues to convey its charm without reservation.
人はその大使の名を
People call that ambassador...
バーチャル大分観光大使と呼ぶ
...the Virtual Oita Tourism Ambassador!
バーチャル O-O-OITA
Virtual O-O-OITA
I wanna be
団長！団長！観光大使！
Danchou! Danchou! Tourism Ambassador!
バーチャル O-O-OITA
Virtual O-O-OITA
I wanna be
団長！団長！観光大使（自称）
Danchou! Danchou! Tourism Ambassador (Self-proclaimed)!
バババ バーチャル大分 世に放つ
V-V-V-Virtual Oita, unleashed upon the world,
バババ バーチャル大分 湯を沸かす
V-V-V-Virtual Oita, boiling the water,
君とバーチャル大分 駆け巡る
Running around Virtual Oita with you.
バババ バーチャル大分 大分 ドーン！
V-V-V-Virtual Oita, Oita, BAM!
バーチャル大分 世に放つ
Virtual Oita, unleashed upon the world,
バーチャル大分 食べ尽くす
eating everything in Virtual Oita,
君とバーチャル大分 駆け巡る
running around Virtual Oita with you.
バババ バーチャル大分 大分 ドーン！
V-V-V-Virtual Oita, Oita, BAM!
大分 ドーン！
Oita, BAM!
団員さん！今年もこうして誕生日をお祝いしてくれて本当にありがとう〜
To all Knights! Thank you so much for celebrating my birthday like this again this year~
新衣装や表情など...どうだったかな？！
How was the new outfit and expressions...?!
少しでも好き...ってなってくれたらノエちゃんとっても嬉しいです
Noe-chan would be very happy if you came to like it even a little bit.
来年も一緒に同じ時間を過ごせますように... 大好きだよ〜♪
I hope we can spend the same time together next year too... I love you~♪